## FULL STACK DEVELOPER (INTERN)

Summary

Diligent Software Engineer offering 4 years in the IT industry with a focus on product design and development. Extensive knowledge of Python and Java . Possess the ability to scale to great extend both in front-end and backend development.

- Highlights
  - Proficient in Python, Java
  - Hands on experience with NodeJS
  - Scripting JavaScript, Bash Scripting
  - Databases MySQL, SQLServer, Oracle10G, MongoDB (NoSQL)
  - Expert in Git Version Control and hands on Git-Flow
- Experience with Apache2.0 web server and Tomcat-7.0 application server.Â
- Frameworks: Bootstrap, JQuery
- Agile development methodologies
- Self-starter
- Team player

## Experience

06/2015 - 04/2016

State Of Virginia - Buckingham, VA Full Stack Developer (Intern)

- Developed **RESTful API webservices** using Java Spring framework.
- Worked on MongoDb and HBase databases.
- Used Git for version control and have worked with GitFlow.
- Contributed to the Development Android application -Â https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.ScanLife.

10/2014 - 05/2015

Steadymd - Chicago, IL Student Assistant Programmer

- Academic and Research Computing Systems, New Jersey Institute of Technology.
- Worked on projects small projects on Linux(SL6) Aided in the setup/upgrade of Kong Nodes for NJIT.

09/2014 - 11/2014

Kas Software Solutions Llc - Pompano Beach, FL Research Assistant

- Worked on a Research Project "Security Learning by Ontology Browsing (SLOB)" for a short duration.
- Redesigned the entire java web application in python in a very short span of time Developed an OWL Parser in python to parse OWL files https://github.com/deeshank/OwlParser.

10/2013 - 08/2014

Cisco India Private Ltd - City, STATE Software Engineer

- Worked with Tools Development & Automation team
- Developed custom tools for the HCS Solution Testing team to enable them to test VOIP call flows via Real phones as well as Camelots (Virtual endpoints)
- Developed the testing tool in Python using TNGpi framework and it is currently being used by the teams to test different call flows.
- Developed the tool using Python Flask framework and Restful web services to run various testcases.

07/2010 - 03/2012

Cognizant Technology Solutions - City, STATE Programmer Analyst

- Worked in Datawarehousing domain as L1 Support Engineer to handle nightly ETL jobs for migrating data from OLTP to OLAP, creating cognos reports, developing ETL mappings for client Orbitz, U.S.
- Worked with Informatica 8.1 and SQL Server Intergration Service (SSIS) for data migration.
- Developed Python scripts to automate various tasks.
- Awarded as Raising Star at Cognizant Technology Solutions.

## Education

2016

New Jersey Institute of Technology - City , State , US Master of Science : Computer Science GPA: 3.87/4.0

Amrita School of Engineering - City , State , India Bachelor of Science : Computer Science & Engineering GPA: 7.9/10.0 Skills

Java, Springs, Python, Flask, Neo4J, NoSQL, Apache, Tomcat, Web2py, MongoDB, HBase, Android, Gradle, Scripting, Bash, PHP, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JQuery, Git, Github, GitFlow, Maven, XML, JSON, BeautifulSoup, REST, RESTAP, Jenkins, Angular JS, Tornado, TNGpi